<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kazi Hasan</title>
    <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kazi Hasan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 17:25:50 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://hasanibnarif.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CONTINUOUS CONTROL WITH DEEP REINFORCEMENT LEARNING</title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/posts/three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 17:25:50 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/posts/three/</guid>
      <description>Paper Link: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1509.02971.pdf
Problem Statement Link to heading DQN was able to solve problems in high-dimensional observation spaces, but action spaces neeeded to be discrete and low-dimensional because each step optimizes over state values. This makes DQN not useful for robotic walking for example. The paper relies on Deep Reinforcement Learning to find multiple coupling action and observation space mappings simultaneously. Physical control task as mentioned have continuous, high-dimensional action spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Analysis on Deep Residual Learning for Image Recognition</title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/posts/two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 22:01:23 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/posts/two/</guid>
      <description>Paper Link: here
Problem Statement Link to heading Introduction
The more deeper a deep neural network is, the more computational complexity is added to the training process. For example, a training a deep neural network may face exploding or vanishing gradiant problem, which result in compromising accuracy of the model. This paper introduced a new technique to combat the problem of training a deep neural network. They present a residual learning framework to ease the training of networks that are substantially deeper than those used previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Analysis on Batch Normalization paper</title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/posts/one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 21:55:45 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/posts/one/</guid>
      <description>Todays Paper : Batch Normalization: Accelerating Deep Network Training by Reducing Internal Covariate Shift Link to heading Paper link: https://arxiv.org/abs/1502.03167
Problem Statement Link to heading Stochastic gradient descent (SGD) is one of the effective ways of training deep networks, and SGD variants such as momentum etc. Batch normalization improves SGD and comes with few advanteages. At the same time, this approach comes with some issues like it requires more sophisticated parameter initilalization and make the training process hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate 3D Bone from DICOM using Deep CNN</title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/publications/two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 23:30:04 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/publications/two/</guid>
      <description>ABSTRACT
Computed tomography (CT) scan or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) have been proposed as methods to measure bone quality and assess fracture risk. However, manual segmentation of MRI/CT is time-consuming which limits its use in clinical practice. It is also costly at the same time. Moreover, the traditional methods that are available to this date are not robust. Our thesis goal is to present an automatic femur segmentation method based on deep Con- volutional Neural Networks (CNNs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local and Global Feature Based Hybrid Deep Learning Model for Bangla Parts of Speech Tagging</title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/publications/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/publications/first/</guid>
      <description>Read more : DOI
Abstract
Parts of Speech (pos) tagging corresponds to techniques of tagging accurate pos tags of each word of a sentence. It is a pivotal and indispensable part of sentiment analysis, synthesizing text to speech, analyzing textual data and many more Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks. Though there are many researches done in the field of languages like English, Chinese, etc. it is still comparatively unexplored for Bangla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Download CV as Pdf from Here Link to heading RESEARCH INTEREST Link to heading Deep Learning Medical Computer Vision 3D Imaging in Radiolog Human Computer Interaction High Performance Computing RESEARCH EXPERIENCE Link to heading 1. Generate 3D Bone from DICOM using Deep CNN
Undergraduate thesis
Supervised by Dr. Mahmuda Naznin (BUET)
We proposed a deep CNN based approach that can segment 3D bone from radiology image
2. Hybrid Deep Learning Model for Bangla Parts of Speech Tagging</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you want to exchange thoughts, please feel free to reach me through any of these :)
Persoanl: hasan.ibn.arif@gmail.com (Preferred)
Office: kazihasan.ibnarif@iqvia.com
Academic: 1605034@ugrad.cse.buet.ac.bd</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hasanibnarif.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description> Police Department Automator (React.js | Node.js | MongoDB) - github link Lines of Action Game (JavaFX) - github link Computer Graphics: Rasterization and Ray Tracing (OpenGL library | C++) - github link C Compiler (Yacc,Lex, C++ | A simple c compiler using lexical analyzer and parser) - github link Something like Pinterest (PostgreSQL, PHP, HTML, CSS | Pinterest website) - github link Angry Birds (C, iGraphics) - github link P2P Messenger in Java (Java Socket) - github link </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
